SUMMARY

Email: Philipmo59@GMAIL.COM

An aspiring Software Developer with 2-3 years of experience working in a professional Research Lab setting, where I developed web applications to automate data interpretation. I am well-versed in Dynamic HTML and Python/SQL for data manipulation and table management. With my extensive experience working in a fast-paced and analytical thinking environment, I am seeking a challenging role that will allow me to further utilize my Software Developer Skills and contribute to the advancement of technology.

EDUCATION

<u>Flatiron Software Engineering Bootcamp, NY | January 2023 — April 2024</u> Certificate of Software Engineering | Key Coursework: Object Oriented Design, Web Development, Data Structures & Algorithms, Relational Database

State University of Binghamton, NY

B.A. in Biology

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

MIRIMUS INC., BROOKLYN, NY

Research and Development Technician | June 2022 - PRESENT

- Developed a Web Application data processing pipeline using DHTML and AppScript for large scale R&D experimental data.
- Worked in a small team to successfully develop and implement two multiplex rt-qPCRs LDTs for the detection of Respiratory and STI pathogens under the conduct and regulations of DOH.
- Worked in a small team to submit an ELISA LDT for the detection of anti-IFN α 2a human autoantibodies.

<u>VIROLOGY/ACCESSIONING TECHNICIAN | Feb 2021 - June 2022</u>

- Ensured quality control of saliva sample processing for the detection of SARS-CoV-2 virus.
- Oversaw accessioning, RNA/DNA extraction process and rt-qPCR testing of client samples.
- Authored and developed Standard Operating Procedures (SOPs) to ensure consistent and compliant execution of laboratory processes.
- Assisted in publishing client results.

SOFTWARE PROJECTS

Research and Development Data Interpretation Application

Web application developed to automate R&D tasks and circumvent dependence on third-party proprietary software associated with an rt-qPCR machine. Processes and visualizes amplification data to provide users with Ct/Cq values based off of the machine's interpretation. Developed using open-source libraries, Papaparse and Simple Statistics.

Online Presence/Contact Information

- Email: Philipmo59@gmail.com
- LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/philipmo59/
- GitHub: https://github.com/Philipmo59